To CP. This is Alpha Two.
指挥所，这里是阿尔法2号
Point One. Nothing out of the ordinary so far.
1号位置目前没有异常
Alpha Two, this is CP. Continue monitoring the situation.
阿尔法2号 这是指挥所，继续监视任务
Emergency kaiju alert.
紧急怪兽警报
YOKOHAMA GATE EMERGENCY UNDERGROUND SHELTER
（紧急地下避难所，横滨入口）
Emergency kaiju alert for Minami, Naka, and Isogo Wards.
南区、中区、矶子三区 发布紧急怪兽警报
All those in the designated zones, please proceed to a shelter immediately.
位在指定区域的民众 请尽快前往避难所
As for the movements of the epicenter…
震央接下来的移动…
The target is moving from Yatobashi to Yamashitacho.
目标正从谷户桥往山下町移动
Estimated full length is 60 meters. Fortitude is a little less than 3.5.
推估全长60米 怪兽规模为3.5以下
-No thermal detection for 3 kilometers. -Roger that.
-3公里范围内没有侦测到热源 -了解
All crafts, begin shooting. I repeat.
全机开始射击，重复一次
-Begin shooting. -Roger that.
-开始射击 -了解
Leading target to TO.
将目标引诱到TO
Shoot.
发射
Will the intimidation work?
威吓射击有用吗？
Which division is coming?
会是哪个部队过来呢？
It's Yokohama, so, the Third Division.
横滨的话，是第3部队吧
Geez, what a mess.
喷得到处都是
We'll be working overtime for a while.
看来得加班一阵子了
All right, let's get to work!
好，开工吧
Yes, sir.
好
Members of the Third Division, who successfully subdued the kaiju,
成功讨伐怪兽的第3部队
are welcomed by the applause of locals.
市民纷纷献上热烈的掌声
The Third Division achieved zero casualties.
达成了零伤亡成绩的第3部队
-Thanks to them… -Captain Ashiro's here!
-感谢他们的… -亚白队长来了
How cool!
好酷哦！
Let us thank them with applause and cheers.
我们用掌声和欢呼来感谢他们
Hey, don't forget to film the victims!
别忘了拍受害者啊
Oh, sorry.
哦，抱歉
-Report back to me later! -Yes, sir!
-之后再跟我报告 -知道了
Captain Ashiro!
亚白队长！
Our work begins after everything has ended.
我们的战斗是在一切结束后才开始
No one gives us attention.
不会有任何人关注
No one thanks us either.
更别说不会收到感谢
But it's our way of battling kaiju,
但这就是我们…
behind the scenes, away from the spotlight.
不为人知与怪兽的战斗
KAFKA HIBINO
（日比野卡夫卡）
Kafka! Izumo Tech wants some samples.
卡夫卡，出云科技说想要一些样本
Thanks.
谢啦
It's no good! I can't cut past the grease.
不行，这边被油包住了切不动
-Bring me the heat chainsaw! -Yes, sir!
-帮我拿电热锯过来 -知道了
Hey, wait a minute! You can't lift that yet!
喂！那个还不能吊起来！
It's this way! Bring the stretcher.
这边，快拿担架过来！
Don't worry, it's just the surface.
别担心，只是皮肉伤而已
I've done this many times. Don't forget to apply for workers' comp.
我处理过很多次了 别忘记申请职灾补助啊
Yes, sir!
好
The Third Division's site is always messy.
第3部队的现场总是一团乱
It's hard to recognize the organs.
都分不出是什么内脏了
Jesus, look at this.
但是这个…
Will we really finish this week?
真的要在这周搞定吗？
Kafka, we're moving you.
卡夫卡，你的负责区域换了
-We don't have enough people over there. -Where is it?
-我们这边缺人手 -哪边？
The intestines.
肠道
-I don't want to! -I already got permission. Let's go!
-我不要！ -我已经取得同意了，走吧
Sorry about that!
节哀顺变
I always hear about it, but is working the intestines that rough?
我是听过传闻 但肠道作业真的很辛苦吗？
Think about it. What's inside the intestines?
只要想想肠子有什么，就明白了吧？
HOW THE BODY WORKS
（身体的组成）
The days we work intestines…
总之清完的那一天…
you can't eat for days.
暂时会吃不下饭吧
I'm so tired!
累死了！
Those baby pandas were so cute!
猫熊宝宝很可爱呢
How will they grow up?
真期待它们之后的成长
I can still smell it.
鼻子里都还有味道…
Let's move on to the next topic.
接着是特辑
Defense Force Third Division, which successfully subdued the kaiju
防卫队第3部队今天出色地讨伐
that suddenly appeared in the streets of Yokohama.
突然出现在横滨的怪兽
The leader of that division is Officer Mina Ashiro-san.
率领这些队员的，就是队长亚白米娜
At the young age of 27,
年仅27岁
she not only became the captain but has already defeated
不仅当上队长，讨伐的怪兽数量
hundreds of kaiju.
更是超过数百只
SPECIAL FEATURE: ZOOMING IN ON THE THIRD DIVISION
（队长：亚白米娜）
Let's defeat all the kaiju together!
我们两人一起消灭所有怪兽吧
Her calm and dignified disposition
她身上冷酷凛然的氛围
makes her one of the most popular captains of the entire Defense Force.
也是所有队长中最有人气的一位
She's rumored to be the next potential Division Commander.
据传她将是未来的师团长候补
She's definitely an up-and-coming star.
今后想必也是备受关注
Why am I over here?
为什么我在这一边啊？
Don't think about it!
别再想了！
Cleaning is important work that also helps people!
清洁也是能帮助人的重要工作
I have a nice room
我住在漂亮的房间
and can eat whatever I want.
吃着喜欢的食物
That's enough, isn't it?
这样不就够了吗？
My head hurts.
头好痛
It's definitely that TV show's fault!
可恶，都是那特辑的错
MONSTER SWEEPER INC.
（Monster Sweeper）
Good morning.
早安
Kafka's here! Come this way!
来了，卡夫卡，过来一下
-I'm going to start getting ready! -All right.
-我先去准备了 -好哦
-Morning, Kafka. -Hey.
-早啊，卡夫卡 -早
This is Ichikawa-kun. He'll work with us part-time, starting today.
这位是今天开始 一起工作的工读生市川
His dream is to join the Defense Force!
他立志要加入防卫队哦
That was his dream too, you know?
这家伙以前的梦想也是哦
He's already given up, and he's a veteran here!
但他早早就放弃 彻底变成这里的老屁股了
This is the worst!
真是糟透了
Toku-san,
阿德
-how's he supposed to react to that? -Why…
-你这样人家不知道怎么回应啦 -为什么？
Why did you give up?
为什么放弃了？
I tried my best, you know?
我也努力过了
But there are so many talented people.
但是人外有人嘛
I hit a wall to my potential.
算是认清自己的能力界线？
-You'll understand when you're older-- -I won't.
-等你上了年纪就懂了… -我才不懂
I'll never give up. I'll never understand until the day I die.
我不会放弃 那种想法我到死都不会懂
Not that I want to.
我也不想懂
-Hey, where are you-- -I'm getting changed.
-喂，你要去哪… -我去换衣服
Geez.
哎呀
I thought you two would get along well.
我还以为你和卡夫卡合得来
That's unfair!
太诈了吧！
No matter how I respond to that, I'd be a pathetic loser!
那种情况下 我怎么回答都像鲁蛇一样
Is it such a bad thing to give up?
放弃真的这么糟糕吗？
All right, let's start.
好咯，开工吧
Team Miike, continue cleaning the bones.
三池班继续清洗骨头
Keep everything intact
-保留原型的部分交给出云科技 -知道了
Team Yoshimura will dismantle the legs. Everything will be discarded.
吉村班负责脚部解体，这边全数销毁
Yes, sir.
好
The newbies get the intestines. Come with me.
新人负责肠道，跟我来
All right! Serves you right!
赞啦，活该！
-Kafka, you're intestines, too. -Me too?
-卡夫卡也跟我去肠道 -我也是啊？
-This is my second day in a row! -You're good at it though.
-我连续两天耶 -谁叫你很擅长清理肠道嘛
Dammit, bring it on!
可恶，要做就做吧！
He always stands up to the challenge in the end.
他虽然满嘴抱怨 但还是会好好面对工作呢
If he had passed, he would've been a great Defense Force member.
如果他能考上 会是个不错的防卫队员吧
Seriously?
真的吗？
He's suffering big time!
难受得要死吧？
Same goes for me.
虽然我也是
Hey, is that all you brought to eat?
你带来的午餐只有那个便当吗？
I don't think I can eat this.
我有点吃不下
I'm sure.
我想也是
-Here. -What is it--
-喂 -怎么样…
Ow!
噢
That's for you. Eat whatever you're able to.
给你吧，能吃多少算多少
You have to get through the day.
还有下午呢
-I'll be fine-- -I'll give you these also.
-我没关系… -这个也给你
These make it much more tolerable.
戴鼻塞工作会好很多
I don't know what you're saying,
我不知道你在说什么
but I seriously don't need those--
但我真的不需要那个
Don't be shy. Just put them on.
少跟我客气，戴戴看啊
Senpai, that's workplace harassment!
前辈，这是职权骚扰！
This is a rite of passage for all newbies.
这是菜鸟的必经之路呢
Carry your own stuff, okay?
自己的东西记得带走啊
-Good work today! -Good work!
-辛苦了
-See you! -Good work today.
-先走了 -今天辛苦了
We got through the smelliest areas.
最臭的部分已经清理完了吧
Senpai.
前辈
Hey, Ichikawa.
哦，市川
Are you here to get back at me for lunch?
你是来报复中午的事情吗？
Thanks to you…
多亏…
Thanks to you, I survived my first day.
多亏你帮忙，我才能撑过第一天
Thank you, sir.
谢谢
That's all.
就这样而已
Goodbye.
我只想说这些
Also, they're raising the age limit to under 33.
还有，他们把 年龄限制放宽到33岁了
To join the Defense Force.
防卫队的招聘条件
Because of the low birthrates.
好像是少子化的关系
It's your life, so, it's none of my business,
其实别人的人生跟我没什么关系
but when you said you gave up,
但是你说到放弃的时候
you looked really sad, that's all.
看起来很落寞的样子
It seriously doesn't matter to me.
说真的我不在乎
If I got it all wrong, you're free to give up all you want.
如果我误会了，你尽管放弃没关系
Bye!
再见
Ichikawa.
市川
Thanks.
谢谢你
You're nicer than you look.
你这个人比我想的好很多呢
I told you that's not what this is about!
所以说不是那样…
Senpai?
前辈？
Yoju?
余兽？
Run, Ichikawa! Get as far away as you can!
市川，快跑！全速离开这里！
Once you're in a safe area, make a report.
到了安全的地方，就通知防卫队
-But senpai, you'd be alone-- -Having two won't make a difference!
-但前辈你一个人… -两个人上也没有用！
You're joining the Force, right?
你要当上队员吧？
Don't die here!
要是死在这里，还想怎样？
Here! I'm over here!
这边！
Over there!
就是那里
I did it.
成功了
Now, I can…
这样就…
Goddammit!
可恶啊！
It's all gone. Your home, my home, our school.
你家、我家和学校，全都被毁了
I won't forgive kaiju!
可恶的怪兽！
I was almost done with all the GlaMon stages!
我差点就要全破《宝古梦》了说！
That's why you're sad?
你伤心的是那件事哦？
I'm sad that Meeko died.
我是因为咪子死掉在伤心
Meeko's your calico cat, right?
咪子是那只三色花猫吗？
-I'm going to join the Defense Force.
-我要成为防卫队员
Hey, you're just a kid!
你这个小鬼在胡说什么？
You're still in elementary school too, Kafka-kun!
卡夫卡你不也是小学生吗？
In that case,
那么
let's bet on who becomes the coolest Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛谁能成为帅气的队员吧
Let's defeat all the kaiju together!
我们两人一起消灭所有怪兽吧
Shit. It wasn't supposed to be like this!
可恶，不应该是这样子的
Shit!
该死
Kaiju don't scare me!
怪兽又怎么样？
Aim for the leg. The leg…
瞄准脚部…
How did I get here?
为什么会变成这样？
Let's bet on who becomes the coolest officer!
我们来比赛谁能成为帅气的队员吧
Ichikawa?
市川？
-You idiot! Why-- -I made the report!
-笨蛋，为什么… -我已经通知防卫队了
That's not what I'm talking about!
谁问你那个？
If I leave you here and run,
如果我把前辈丢在这里逃跑的话
I'd never become a Defense Force officer!
我一定会无法成为队员的！
WE REGRET TO INFORM YOU…
（很遗憾通知您…）
Shit.
可恶
Why am I so weak?
为什么我这么无力？
I haven't grown at all.
什么都没有改变
I can't even protect my own video game, a friend's cat,
自己的游戏机、朋友的猫
even my own kohai!
就连一位后辈都保护不了
Shit!
可恶！
Target defeated. I see an injured civilian.
已击败目标，似乎有伤员
Rescue operation will continue.
转为救护行动
Igarashi, Takaragi, look after the injured.
五十岚、宝木，伤员交给你们了
Everyone else, follow me.
其他人跟我来
We'll look for any remaining yoju.
搜索四周是否还有余兽
-Are you all right? -Don't move. Stay still.
-你还好吗？ -别动，保持这样
Mina is so cool.
米娜真厉害啊
She crushed that frightening monster with one blow.
一瞬间就把那么可怕的怪兽给…
She's somewhere far away from me now.
她已经到我无法可及的地方了
Senpai.
前辈
After the kaiju appeared
怪兽出现后
and you told me to run,
你叫我快跑
if you didn't save me then,
那时，如果不是你救了我
I would've died today.
我今天早就死了
You were really cool.
你真的超帅的
Let's bet on who becomes the coolest Defense Force officer!
我们来比赛谁能成为帅气的队员吧
I really think you should be a Defense Force officer.
你果然该去当防卫队员
Well, it's your life, so it doesn't matter to me.
嗯，反正是你的自由，跟我没关系
You're right.
也对
When will I stop looking away from what's important!?
我到底想视而不见到什么时候啊？
Thanks, Ichikawa.
谢谢你，市川
You're a really good guy.
你果然是个好人啊
I don't think it's a bad thing to give up,
我不觉得放弃是件坏事
but it's bad to lie to yourself!
但欺骗自己并不是件好事
I'm going to try joining the Defense Force again--
我要再次立志成为防卫队…
What?
什么？
I found you.
找到你了
Kai… Kai…
怪…
Senpai?
前辈？
Does your injury hurt?
伤口会痛吗？
Senpai!
前辈！
What?
咦？
-What? -Ichikawa, it's me!
-什么？ -市川，是我！
Don't get so scared!
别吓到后退啊
OH…
（噢…）
He's reporting you.
他要通知防卫队了
Let's run, senpai!
快逃吧，前辈！
What?
什么？
When you encounter a kaiju,
遇到怪兽时
you should attack its legs,
应该先攻击脚
tie it up, and make sure it can't move.
将脚绑起来，让怪兽动弹不得
It's a little scary.
有点可怕耶
What is?
怕什么？
Imagining what it's like to fight a kaiju that's so much bigger than you.
想到自己要跟大好几倍的怪兽战斗
It'll be okay.
放心吧
Anytime that happens,
到那个时候
I'll be right next to you!
我会一直陪在你身边
Liar.
骗子
Yes.
是
A kaiju appeared at South Yokohama Hospital?
横滨南综合医院出现怪兽？
No, there's no problem.
不会，没问题
I'll dispatch my officers right away.
我马上出动队员
Yes, we'll kill it.
开始扑杀怪兽
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：唐咏杰